（猿投山(さなげやま)）ぐっ！ 食らえ！
必殺 一振全斬剣(いっしんぜんざんけん)！
Eat this!
Finishing Move: All-Out Blade Strike!
（縫(ぬい)）ほいっ
Hup!
（猿投山）うっ… ぐはっ
Go right back to being a naked ape!
裸の猿に戻りなよ
Impossible!
（猿投山）バカな！
Hup!
（縫）ほいっ
Here we go!
（縫）よいしょ
Ta-dah!
じゃーん
...That's...
（流子(りゅうこ)）それは…
Yep! It's the other half
of your Sword Scissor!
（縫）そう 君のハサミの半分
Fresh from your dad's corpse!
君のお父さんから
僕がもらったの
Wait... It was you?
（流子）まさか 貴様…
Sure was!
そう 僕だよ
I was the one who killed your father!
君のお父さんを殺したのは
Bitch!
貴様！
Tell me!
答えろ なぜ父さんを殺した
Why did you kill my dad?!
EPISODE 12
SPIT YOUR
SADNESS AWAY
This is a world tailored to someone's whims and fancies
dareka ga katteni kimeta readymade na
I'll break free of its shackles
kyou wo nugisutete
RYUUKO
MATOI
And sprint toward my goal
hadashi de hashitte iku
Even if I lose my way
machigattatte
GAMAGOORI IRA
SANAGEYAMA UZU
JAKUZURE NONON
INUMUTA HOUKA
Or trip and fall
korondatte
INUMUTA HOUKA
MANKANSHOKU FAMILY
Those wounds will still create
surimuita itami mo
MANKANSHOKU
MAKO
MIKISUGI
AIKUROU
KINAGASE
TSUMUGU
An original future for me
original na ashita ni naru
KIRYUUIN
SATSUKI
I hold my destiny in my own hands
tsukiageta kono te ni nigirishimeta
And it shines ever so brightly
chikai ga hikari ni natte
So until the day I reach you
itsuka kimi ni todoku sono shunkan made
I don't have the time to sit around crying
naiteru hima nante nai kara
My burning passion pours out from within me
hamidashite shimatta atsui omoi ga
And shines like a star in the night sky
yozora de kagayaki dasu
I think I now understand
umarete kita imi ga
Why I was born
wakatta ki ga shita
I'll make all of my dreams come true
negaigoto wa zenbu kono te de
With my own hands
kanaeru
My dad told me that if I took this scissor,
I'd be sure to find the person who killed him!
（流子）父さんは言った
“このハサミを持っていれば 必ず
自分を殺した相手にたどりつく”と
What do you know, he was right!
そのとおりだったよ
You were the one in my house
that day, weren't you?!
あのとき私の家にいたのは
お前だな！
Yup, I sure was!
（縫）うん そのとおり
Why?
（流子）なぜだ
なぜ父さんを殺した
Why did you kill him?
You know the answer
to that question already.
その答えは君が知っている
Who, me? Don't give me that crap!
（流子）私が？ ふざけるな
私は父さんのことを何も知らない
I don't know anything about my dad!
Your outfit says otherwise, though.
（縫）でも 着ているじゃない
（流子）着ている？ 鮮血(せんけつ)のことか
Outfit?
You mean Senketsu?
Yup. Your dad crossed a line
mankind was never meant to cross.
そう 君のお父さんは人間の手が
触れちゃいけないものに触れた
タブーってやつね
He committed a taboo.
But taboos sure feel nice, don't they?
（縫）でもタブーって
いい手触りなんだよね
What's with her hand?
（鮮血）何だ この女の手
冷たすぎる
It's freezing!
Wow, it's silky-smooth!
ん〜 すべすべ
さすが生命戦維(せんい)100パーセント
You can tell it's 100% genuine Life Fiber.
（流子）はぐらかすな！
Don't dodge the issue!
Please. I'm doing nothing of the sort.
（縫）やだな
はぐらかしてなんかない
But now that we've met here,
I want us to have lots of fun!
こうして２人が出会えたんだから
もっと楽しいことしようよ
Screw you!
ふざけんな！
父さんを殺した相手と なんで！
Why would I play friends
with my dad's killer?!
You're so narrow-minded.
心が狭いな〜 憎しみと愛は裏表
Love and hate are two sides
of the same coin, you know.
The better an outfit's lining,
the better its stitching is too.
裏地がしっかりしている服ほど
仕立てがいいものよ
That is to say, the more you hate someone,
the more you can love them in turn.
つまり憎しみが深いほど
愛も深まる
深まるわけないだろうが！
My ass, you can!
（縫）まあまあ
怒った顔もすてきよ 流子ちゃん
There, there.
You look wonderful
even when you're mad, Ryuuko.
（流子）うっせえ
Calm down, Ryuuko.
（鮮血）落ち着け 流子
お前の血が熱くなってる
Your blood's boiling.
興奮し過ぎだ　うっ
You're too agitated!
Hey!
（マコ）あっ！ また赤い糸だ
It's another red thread!
Is that the Nexus Thread?
（蟇郡(がまごおり)）あれが絆糸(ばんし)か　まずいぞ
This is trouble!
Makes me want to see you...
（縫）裸の君が見たいな！
naked!
What?
（流子）何！
アハハ
（鮮血）フン！
...Oh—
Now!
（流子）今だ！
That Godrobe's something else!
It has more than one Nexus Thread, huh?
絆糸は１本じゃなかった
ということね
That's right.
（鮮血）ああ そうだ
You won't unravel me that easily.
その程度でバラバラになるほど
私はやわじゃない
Wow, amazing!
すてき すてき〜
Trust Dr. Matoi to have
something like that up his sleeve!
こんなの隠してたなんて
さすがは纏(まとい)博士だわ
I fell hook, line, and sinker for it.
まんまと だまされた
（一身(いっしん)）ん？ 誰だ お前は
Who are you?
I came to play.
（縫）遊びに来たの
（一身）遊びだと？
Play?
SIX MONTHS AGO
MATOI UNDERGROUND RESEARCH FACILITY
（縫）
先生がいろいろと—
I heard you were up to
something interesting, you see.
面白いことをしてる
って聞いたんでね
僕とも遊んでよ
Let me in on the fun.
（一身）なるほど
I see.
俺の研究を嗅ぎつけてきた
というわけか
So you caught wind of
my research and came here.
（縫）うん　知り合いに
持って帰る約束してるの
Yup.
I promised someone I know that
I'd bring your findings back to them.
And it's important to
keep your promises, right?
約束は守らないとね
（一身）フン
（一身）フン！
（縫）あばっ
Hup!
ほいっ
（一身）フン
ふーん 形状記憶白衣か
A shape-memorizing lab coat, huh?
That ability shows that
it's fitted with Life Fibers too.
その力 その服にも
生命戦維が仕込んであるんだね
Great.
よかった〜
Now I don't have to hold back!
本気で遊べるね！
Don't be such a wet blanket.
（縫）ん〜 出し惜しみはやめて
You've gotta take games seriously too,
or else you won't have fun in life!
遊びも全力で
じゃなきゃ人生 楽しくないよ
うりゃ！
This is what I've poured
my heart and soul into creating.
（一身）これこそ
俺が命を賭して開発してきたもの
生命戦維の生命そのものを断つ
その名もずばり…
It cuts the very life of Life Fibers.
Its name: the Sword Scissors!
SWORD
SCISSORS
I see you're not very good
at naming things, Doc.
先生 ネーミングセンスはないね
A scientist cares not for aesthetics!
（一身）学者にウケはいらん
All we need is for
our research to bear fruit!
その研究成果さえ確かならな！
（縫）ふ〜ん
It's not about how pretty it is,
but how you use it, huh?
まさしく なんとかと
ハサミは使いようか
（一身）フン おりゃ！
まさしく なんとかと
ハサミは使いようか
Oh, so scary!
危ない 危ない
おりゃ！
Looks like wielding those scissors
takes a lot out of you.
（縫）どうやら そのハサミ—
使うのに ずいぶん
体力がいるみたいね
もう少し 体 鍛えないと
You need to strengthen your body.
Mind your own business.
（一身）ほっとけ
学者は60代からが盛りよ
Scientists peak in their sixties.
Wow, they really do nullify Life Fibers.
あっ ホントに
生命戦維の活動を止めるんだ
さすが纏先生
このハサミの威力は大したものね
Way to go, Dr. Matoi.
These scissors are really powerful.
（刺す音）
（一身）ぐわっ
（縫）どう？
So how does it feel to have the creation you poured
your heart and soul into rip out your heart and soul?
自分が命を懸けて作った研究で
命を絶たれる気分は—
I bet it feels out of this world!
最高でしょ？
I'm so nice, aren't I?
僕 優しいよね
（一身）くっ… 勝手なことを
...Stop mouthing off...
（縫）じゃあ これ
頂いていくから
Anyway, I'll be taking this with me, okay?
...Dad...
（流子）父さん　父さん！
Dad!
Begone!
（縫）フン！
（一身）ぐはっ
（縫）えいっ！
Dad?
（流子）父さん？
So he had one half of
the Sword Scissors stolen
（鮮血）
断(た)ち斬(き)りバサミは奪われたが—
but still managed to
conceal my existence.
私の存在は隠し通したわけか
I'm impressed, Dr. Matoi.
さすがは纏博士だ
So the woman I saw back then was you?!
じゃあ あのとき私が見たのは
お前だったのか！
You got it!
そういうこと
If I'd known a girl as cute
as you was on her way,
君みたいな かわいい子が
来るんだったら—
逃げずに待ってればよかった
I would've stayed right there
and waited for you.
You bitch!
ふざけたことを！
そんなんで
お父様の敵(かたき)を取るつもり？
Do you think you can
avenge your dad with that?
Not happening, girl!
無理 無理 無理
We'll see about that!
（流子）言わせておけば〜！
Stop it, Ryuuko.
（鮮血）やめろ 流子
その血の熱さは危険だ
Your blood grows dangerously hot!
If this keeps up,
I won't be able to control myself!
このままだと 私は自分を保てない
（流子）ハァ
...No...
（皐月(さつき)）いかん
それが狙いか 針目(はりめ)縫
Is this what you were after, Harime Nui?
I'm going down there.
降りる
Very nice!
いいわ いいわ
楽しくなってきた
Things are getting fun!
This doesn't look good.
（犬牟田(いぬむた)）ダメだ
彼女 完全に暴走している
She's gone completely berserk.
What?!
Are you saying she was
overwhelmed by her Godrobe?
（蛇崩(じゃくずれ)）神衣の力に
飲み込まれたってわけ？
Matoi is in grave peril.
（犬牟田）
このままでは纏の体がもたない
In just a few minutes,
she'll die from blood loss!
数分で失血死してしまうだろう
What? Death from blood loss?
えー！ 失血死？
りゅうけつしないと
DEATH
FROM
BLOOD
LOSS
FROM
BLOOD
LOSS
FROM
BLOOD
LOSS
She needs a blood transformation!
（蛇崩）輸血でしょ
You mean "transfusion".
My dad steals his patients' blood
so he can sell it off at a high price later,
ウチのお父さん—
仕事で人の血 盗んで
高く売ったりしてるから—
失血死なら
いっぱい見たことがある
so I've seen plenty of people
die from excess blood loss!
Wait a minute.
What is that supposed to mean?
ちょっと待て それはどういう…
People die when they're killed by blood loss!
人は失血死すると
死んでしまうのです
...Right...
当たり前だ
It is not right!
当たり前ではありません
It's not okay for Ryuuko to die!
流子ちゃんが
死んでいいはずがない！
私も闇医者の娘の端くれ
I have to do my job as the
daughter of a back-alley doctor!
Say no to death from blood loss!
ストップ ザ 失血死
ストップ ザ 血液泥棒〜
Say no to blood theft!
大変なことになっているな
This has become quite the debacle.
Sanageyama.
猿投山
Oh, you were okay, wild monkey?
あら 無事だったの 山猿さん
Thanks to you, I was able to
obtain some data on Nexus Threads.
（犬牟田）おかげで絆糸にまつわる
データが取れたよ
Until I settle my score with Matoi,
纏との決着をつけるまで
俺は死なん
I can't possibly die.
...Sanageyama, you...
猿投山 お前は…
Put on some clothes.
服を着ろ
Our fears have been realized.
（美木杉(みきすぎ)）最悪だ
くっ… 足止めしてくれ 紬(つむぐ)
Please hold her down, Tsumugu.
（黄長瀬(きながせ)）わかった
Got it.
Lady Satsuki, will you be all right?
（蟇郡）皐月様 ご無事ですか
The voting grounds are a lost cause.
（皐月）闘兵場(とうひょうじょう)の倒壊は
もはや止められん
You four are to evacuate the students.
お前たちは生徒を非難させろ
I had no idea a Godrobe
could be this powerful.
（蛇崩）神衣に ここまでの力が…
I'll stop her.
（皐月）私はヤツを止める
Life Fiber Override:
人衣(じんい)圧倒
Godrobe Junketsu!
GOD
ROBE
JUNKETSU
（皐月）ここは任せたぞ
（四天王）はっ！
I'm counting on you.
Yes, ma'am!
Wait, Ryuuko!
（マコ）待ってよー 流子ちゃん
You're wasting your blood!
もったいないよ
血は高く売れるよー
It's worth good money, you know!
Back-Alley Doctor
Mankanshoku
Oh, Mako.
（薔薇蔵(ばらぞう)）おう マコ どうした？
（マコ）父ちゃん
What's wrong?
Dad!
We came all the way here to watch
Ryuuko fight live, up close and personal!
流子ちゃんの戦いが生で見たくて
ここまで来たんだ
Sis, show us somewhere we can sneak in.
（又郎(またろう)）姉ちゃん
潜り込める場所 教えてよ
Where are the voting grounds?
（好代(すくよ)）
闘兵場はどこなのかしら？
（ガッツ）ガッツガッツ
そんなのんきなこと
言ってる場合じゃないよ
This is no time for that!
Back-alley doctor Mankanshoku,
闇医者 満艦飾(まんかんしょく)の出番だよ！
it's your time to shine!
Back-Alley Doctor
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor On Call
（薔薇蔵）ん？
（好代）あら〜
I don't really get what's
going on, but leave it to me!
（薔薇蔵）
何だかわからねえが 任せろ！
Hang in there, Ryuuko!
（マコ）待っててね 流子ちゃん
You've got a back-alley doctor's
daughter on your side!
あなたには闇医者の娘の
端くれがついてる！
（流子）ハァ ハァ…
（流子）ぐわっ
アハハハ… いいわ いいわ
Excellent!
It keeps getting more and more monstrous!
どんどん化け物になってく
生命戦維は そうでなきゃ
That's what Life Fiber's gotta be like!
So even you ended up
consumed by your clothes, huh?
（黄長瀬）やっぱり お前も
服に飲み込まれちまったな
（縫）何？ 君は
What's your deal?
I see no need to introduce myself!
（黄長瀬）名乗る必要はない！
You're getting in the way of my fun.
君 邪魔だよ
Like I said, you're in the way.
邪魔なんだって
ハァ… トラップってわけ
It was a trap?
Great job, Tsumugu.
さすが紬だ 感謝する
You have my thanks.
This is a special adhesive round.
早い話が強力な
のり付けみたいなもんだ
Long story short,
it has a kind of starching effect.
But there's no guarantee that the
person wearing the outfit will survive.
だが これを使うと
着ている人間の命も保証できない
Forgive me, Ryuuko.
（美木杉）ごめんな 流子君
She noticed me?
気付かれた？
この距離で まさか
At this distance?!
It can't be.
Shit!
しまった
（流子）ハァ…
Not on my watch!
行かせねえよ
Another trap?
（縫）また トラップ
Goodness me, how annoying.
まったく うっとうしい
Why, if it isn't Lady Satsuki.
あら 皐月様 すてきな衣装ね
That's a wonderful outfit you're wearing.
Even Kiryuuin's here now?
鬼龍院(きりゅういん)まで登場だと
何を考えている 針目縫
What are you plotting, Harime Nui?
The Godrobe that
...Dr. Matoi Isshin created...
纏一身先生が作り上げた神衣
Don't you want to see
how strong it is? I sure do.
どこまで力があるか
見てみたいでしょ？
それとも纏一身に
まんまと欺かれた意趣返しか？
Seems more like you're trying to get revenge for how badly Matoi Isshin outsmarted you.
Huh?
You were so distracted by the Sword Scissors that you didn't notice the Godrobe he was developing in secret.
（皐月）
断ち斬りバサミに気を取られ—
ひそかに開発していた神衣の存在に
気付かなかったのは 貴様のミスだ
That's your fault.
And you even lost your left eye.
しかも左目を潰された
That side of yours isn't
cute at all, Lady Satsuki.
（縫）皐月様のそういうとこ
ホントにかわいくない
That's fine.
（皐月）それでいい
Nothing good ever happens
to things you find cute.
貴様にかわいいと呼ばれると
ろくなことはない
On that note, Ryuuko's absolutely adorable.
（縫）
その点 流子ちゃんはかわいいわ
いちずに僕を狙って
She's coming after me
with everything she's got.
Come to your senses,
目を覚ませ 纏流子！
Matoi Ryuuko!
No use, huh?
（皐月）無駄か
Yup.
うん 無駄 無駄 無駄
Useless, useless, useless!
（皐月）下がれ
（縫）あ…
Stand back.
In that case, it is
...my job to take her down—
ならば ヤツをしとめるのは
私の仕事だ
to finish off the girl who's been consumed by her Life Fibers' destructive impulses!
生命戦維の破壊衝動に
飲み込まれたヤツに—
とどめを刺すのはな！
（縫）ん〜 それはそれで面白いわ
That sounds interesting in its own right.
Get back, Tsumugu.
（無線:美木杉）
下がれ 紬 そこは危険だ
You're not safe there.
Gotcha.
（黄長瀬）わかった
（皐月）フン！
ぬおー
（皐月）ぬおー
Amazing!
（縫）
すごい すごーい　２人だけの世界
とても入り込めない
You two are in your own little world!
There's no room for anyone else!
"And it'd be amusing
if you took each other out."
（皐月）
ついでに共倒れになれば面白い
そう思っているな
I know that's what you're thinking.
I wouldn't dream of it!
（縫）とんでもない
Too bad that's not going to happen.
（皐月）だが そうはならん
A girl who's just being worn by her own
Godrobe is no match for me, Kiryuuin Satsuki!
神衣に着られているだけの
女など—
この鬼龍院皐月の敵ではない！
（縫）うひょー
Here I come,
（皐月）いくぞ 纏
Matoi!
Stop!
ダメ〜
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
（マコ）流子ちゃ〜ん
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Ryuuko!
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Back-Alley Doctor
On Call
Mankanshoku
Ryuuko!
（マコ）流子ちゃ〜ん
流子ちゃん 流子ちゃん…
Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko!
Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko!
流子ちゃん 流子ちゃん…
Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko! Ryuuko!
Stop!
ダメ〜
Stop it, Ryuuko!
ダメだよ 流子ちゃん
こんなの流子ちゃんらしくないよ！
This isn't like you at all!
What are you getting in the way for?
何 邪魔してんのよ！ あっ
Huh?
おろっ
Hold your tongue and watch!
黙って見ていろ
Did you forget what you said to me?
流子ちゃん 言ってたじゃない
You said it wasn't about
avenging your dad,
“お父さんの敵を取るんじゃない”
but getting to know him better!
“お父さんのことが
知りたいんだ”って
（流子）フン！
But you're just a monster right now!
でも 今のまんまじゃ
ただの怪物だよ
You're kicking, screaming,
and destroying our school!
ほえて暴れて学校 壊して
これじゃマコと一緒だよ
You're acting just like I did!
Like I did when I let the
Fight Club thing go to my head!
喧嘩(けんか)部で舞い上がってたマコと！
（流子）フンッ
Back then, you brought me
back to my senses!
あのとき 流子ちゃんは
私を正気に戻してくれた
So now it's my turn to do the same!
だから 今度は私の番
（流子）ハァ… ぐるる…
（マコ）フン！
I will bring you back!
私が流子ちゃんを取り戻す〜
...Mako...
マコ
...I'm... back... to... normal...
（マコ）たー！ たー！ たー…
（流子）よせ やめろ　痛(いて)て
...You... can... stop... now...
Geez!
もう！
It's all okay now.
（流子）もう 大丈夫だから
Calm down!
おっ 落ち着け　痛っ よせ
Ow! Stop it!
あっ！ 流子ちゃん
Ryuuko!
Thank you.
ありがとう
...Ryuuko...
（鮮血）流子
Sorry I dragged you along
with my rampage, Senketsu.
鮮血も 巻き添えにして悪かった
Don't be.
（鮮血）
いや お前が無事でよかった
I'm just glad you're all right.
You nearly died of blood loss, you know?
もう 失血死するとこだったんだよ
You stupid idiot dummy!
（マコ）あれ？
流子ちゃん？ 流子ちゃん？
Huh? Ryuuko?
Ryuuko!
流子ちゃん 流子ちゃん！
死んだ？
Ryuuko! Ryuuko!
Did she die?!
She's just unconscious.
（皐月）気を失っているだけだ
Mankanshoku,
満艦飾 貴様のおかげで
命をつないだな
it's thanks to you
that she was able to survive.
L-Lady Satsuki!
さ… 皐月様　なぜ ここに
Why are you here?
Wait, you know my name?
てか 皐月様が私の名前を？
てか 流子ちゃん しっかりして！
Wait, Ryuuko! Pull yourself together!
Whoa!
って わあ！ 私 全身が
こんがり真っ黒に焼けてるよ？
My entire body's been singed pitch-black!
Wow! It's like I got a free tan!
すごい！ タダで
日サロ行ったみたい ラッキー
Lucky!
やれやれだな
Good grief.
Thanks, Tsumugu.
すまなかったな 紬
なんとか こいつを使わずに済んだ
We somehow managed to pull
through without using this thing.
I couldn't make a move.
手が出せなかった
あの３人の女たちに
手を出すことができなかった
I couldn't make a single move
on those three women.
当然だろ　ああなると
もう人間を超えた怪物だ
Of course not.
In the state they're in, they're like
monsters that have transcended humanity.
（黄長瀬）クソッ
訓練のやり直しだ
Shit!
I need to start training from scratch.
...Aww...
あーあ 何だかつまんない
終わり方になっちゃった
That was such a boring ending.
Harime Nui.
（皐月）針目縫 今後
本能字(ほんのうじ)学園への立ち入りは禁ずる
From now on, you are barred from
setting foot in Honnouji Academy.
Huh?
I'll take care of Matoi Ryuuko
and her Godrobe myself.
纏流子と神衣の件は
全て私が始末をつける
If you try pulling anything funny,
いらぬ手出しをした場合は—
I will show you no mercy,
Grand Couturier or not.
たとえグランクチュリエだろうと
容赦はしない
That's awfully cold of you.
（縫）あら つれないわ
Get lost.
（皐月）去れ
（縫）はいはい わかりました
Okay, okay.
I understand!
Just kidding!
（縫）なんてね
Before the bell rings
chime ga naru mae ni
I sneak out of school
kugurinuketa
Avoiding the adults' vacant stares
otonatachi no haiiro no me
The pointless conversations
tawai no nai kaiwa
Keep going on and on
togirenu mama
As I walk down the slope
sakamichi wo kudatteku
I have nothing to do
nani wo suru demo naku
And nowhere to go
yuku ate sae mo naku
Right now, all I do
tada atashi ima wa ne
Is ignore any and all warnings
donna chuukoku mo mimi wo surinukeru
Because I still want to be free
mada mada suki ni sasete
I'm sorry, but it's not like me
gomen ne e ni kaita you na
To be an exemplary student
yuutosei wa rashiku nai wa
So I undo two of my shirt buttons
shirt no button wo futatsu hazushite
And take the back alley
rojiura no nukemichi
A path of mysterious sweet temptation
amai yuuwaku wa michi
Some things I've kept hidden from everyone
dare ni mo mada hanashite nai
But tonight, I will reveal my secrets to you
atashi no himitsu wo kon'ya oshiete ageru
SEVERAL
DAYS
LATER
歩けるようになったようだな
I see you're on your feet again.
（流子）針目縫はどこだ
Where's Harime Nui?
Why do you want to know?
（皐月）なぜ それを知りたい
父親の敵だからか
Because she killed your father?
（流子）そのとおりだ
Exactly.
（皐月）
纏一身から断ち斬りバサミを
奪えと命じたのは私だ
I was the one who ordered her to
take the Sword Scissors from Matoi Isshin.
If you must resent someone, resent me.
恨むなら私を恨め
What?
（流子）何だと？
"Why was Matoi Isshin killed?"
（皐月）なぜ纏一身が殺されたか
"What is a Godrobe?"
神衣とは 生命戦維とは何か
"What are Life Fibers?"
その全ての謎は私が知っている
I know the answers
to all of those questions.
...Then let's do this, here and no—
（流子）だったら今ここで…
（皐月）勝てるか 今のお前に
Do you really think you can
win as you currently are?
先日の暴走で お前の体は
まだダメージを負っているはずだ
I doubt you've recovered fully
from that rampage the other day.
Shut up!
言うな！
You have my gratitude, Matoi Ryuuko.
礼を言うぞ 纏流子
くっ… 礼？
Gratitude?
That's right.
（皐月）ああ そうだ　貴様が
四天王と戦ってくれたおかげで—
Thanks to your battles with the Four Devas,
I've been able to perfect the Ultima Uniforms.
極(ごく)制服の最終調整ができた
Now I can put them to use in actual battle.
これで実戦に投入できる
Say what?
（流子）何？
At long last, Honnouji Academy
will conquer every school in the country.
（皐月）いよいよ 本能字学園の
全国学園支配が完成する
Is that why you held the Naturals Election
and the King of the Hill battles?
壊惨総戦挙(かいさんそうせんきょ)も塔首(とうしゅ)頂上決戦も
それが狙いだったのか？
Correct.
そういうことだ
本能字学園は１週間後—
Honnouji Academy will,
in one week's time,
subjugate every school in
the west that dares oppose us.
我々に反抗する西の学園勢力を
一気に制圧する
We will go on a Battlefield Trip
to conquer the big three!
三都制圧襲学(しゅうがく)旅行である
CONQUEST
OF THE
BIG THREE
BATTLEFIELD
TRIP
Just sit back and watch.
貴様はここで
指をくわえて見ていろ
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
What is youth?
（鮮血）
青春とは何だ 青い春だ
なぜ春が青いのか 未熟だからだ
It is the springtime of life!
WHY
And why is it the springtime of life?
NOT IN BLOOM
For it is not in full bloom!
落ち込むも未熟
信念に突っ走るも未熟
Depressed? You're still budding.
BUDDING
Chasing after your ideals?
You're still budding.
BUDDING
...I say that as I—
なんて私も…
うわー！
Egad!
EGAD!
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"Crazy For You"!
次回 キルラキル
「君に薔薇薔薇… という感じ」
EPISODE THIRTEEN
CRAZY FOR YOU